Find your way home.
Cold Mountain is a war, history, adventure film directed by Anthony Minghella.
In this classic story of love and devotion set against the backdrop of the
American Civil War, a wounded Confederate soldier named W.P.
Inman deserts his unit and travels across the South, aiming to return to
his young wife, Ada, who he left behind to tend their farm.
As Inman makes his perilous journey home, Ada struggles to keep their home intact with the
assistance of Ruby, a mysterious drifter sent to help her by a kindly neighbor.
Inman, played by Jude Law.
Ada Monroe, played by Nicole Kidman.
Ruby Thewes, played by Renée Zellweger.
Maddy, played by Eileen Atkins.
Stobrod Thewes, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Reverend Veasey, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Cold Mountain is a 2003 epic period war drama film
written and directed by Anthony Minghella.
The film is based on the bestselling 1997 novel by Charles Frazier.
It stars Jude Law, Nicole Kidman, and Renée Zellweger with Eileen Atkins, Brendan Gleeson, Kathy Baker, Philip Seymour
Hoffman, Natalie Portman, Jack White, Giovanni Ribisi, Donald Sutherland, and Ray Winstone in supporting roles.
The film tells the story of a wounded deserter from the Confederate army close to the end of
the American Civil War, who journeys home to reunite with the woman he loves.
The film was a co-production of companies in
Italy, Romania, and the United States.
Cold Mountain was released theatrically on December 25, 2003, by Miramax Films.
It emerged a critical and commercial success, grossing over $173 million.
It received seven nominations at the 76th Academy Awards, including Best
Actor (Law), with Zellweger winning Best Supporting Actress.
The film explores themes of love of one's life, loss of
loved one, desertion, rape attempt, somber.
The tone is emotional.